carlyforpresident.com 2016-03-21

# Privacy Policy | Carly Fiorina for President 2016

This document describes the privacy practices of Carly for President (the "Privacy Policy").

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you, including information gathered when you visit the campaign's website located at CarlyForPresident.com, the campaign's social media pages, the campaign's mobile site or downloadable mobile applications (collectively, the "Site"), and information we may receive from third parties or affiliates, how we may use that information, whether we disclose that information to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, the information. We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of visitors to our website.

By using the Site, you consent to the use and disclosure of information as described in this Privacy Policy.

Because we care about the safety and privacy of children online, we comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA"). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulations establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. Our site is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and we have designed our sites to block our knowing acceptance of information from children under 13 whenever age-related information is requested.

We collect two types of information: personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you ("Personally Identifiable Information"). We also may collect information that by itself typically cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information (e.g., age, profession or gender), IP addresses, browser types, domain names, and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our Site ("Non- Personally Identifiable Information"). 

When you make a contribution through our Site, any credit card information provided is only used to immediately process your donation. We do not retain your credit card information once the donation is processed. Carly for President has adopted security measures to protect your financial information. We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving financial data from our site.

We use log files and Google Analytics to assess the aggregate level of traffic on CarlyForPresident.com, including what pages people are visiting, and to diagnose any potential problems with the Site. This log file contains an IP address that gives us insight on the general geographic area of visitors but not information on a specific individual. We do not use log files to track a particular individual's use of our site. Google Analytics will place cookies on your computer that will generate information that we select about your use of the Site, including your computer's IP address. That information will be transmitted to and stored by Google. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. Please note that by doing so, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Site. The use of cookies by Google Analytics is covered by Google's privacy policy. All users remain anonymous unless they choose to give us personally identifiable information.

Our site contains opportunities for a visitor to share content, and messages to friends and family. Some features of our site may allow you to store addresses for easy retrieval and reuse at a later time. This information is stored for your convenience. We use cookies to personalize and customize your interaction on our site, and to provide you with the best possible online experience.

This site may include very small files provided by one or more online advertising networks that help them more precisely to target advertising to users, based on users' activity on sites within those networks. These files do not access or use information by which users can be personally identified. If you wish, you can prevent these files from using non-personal information about you by either deleting the cookie folder in your browser or by putting your browser's Privacy setting higher, but doing so will mean that you will not be presented with advertising that reflects the way that you use our, and other, websites -- and may well adversely affect your experience of websites that use cookies to enhance or personalize that experience. For more information about digital advertising, or to opt out of targeted ads, visit: https://www.aboutads.info/choices/.

Personally Identifiable Information we collect may include your name, email addresses, postal addresses, ZIP code, telephone number, credit card information, date of birth, gender, age, user name and password, and other information either desirable or necessary to provide quality services to our customers and visitors. 

To the extent we are able to do so, we may link your Non-Personally Identifiable Information with your Personally Identifiable Information. We may also link information collected online with information we collect offline or that is collected online by third parties. 

Carly for President may provide or sell your email address or other personal information to third parties for fundraising or other purposes. Additionally, we may share your personal information with select third parties who offer goods or services we think may be of interest to you. From time to time, we may partner with other organizations or companies to provide co-sponsored or co-branded promotions, services or events and may share your personal information with our co-sponsor(s) and partners. Additionally, Carly for President may provide your personal information to service providers or contractors to perform functions on its behalf, such as, but not limited to, companies or individuals hired to communicate news, deliver our promotional materials via e-mail and direct mail, promote our social media presence and activities, to process credit card payments and to assist us with sending communications and performing other marketing and support functions. Also, we may use third-party social media platforms, including third-party social media websites, to communicate with you.

We also may share with third parties aggregated demographic and statistical information that is not personally identifiable.

Carly for President also may disclose an individual's personal information:  

  * to a person who in our reasonable judgment is seeking the information as an agent of the individual; 
  * in situations where sharing or disclosing your information is required in order to offer you products or services you desire;
  * to a third party or parties, where disclosure is required or permitted by law; and
  * if, in our reasonable judgment, it is necessary enforce compliance with our internal policies or the Terms of Use or to protect our Site, supporters, or others.

We may be required to use or disclose your information in connection with a legal action or other proceeding, including without limitation, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency's request.

This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Carly for President. This Privacy Policy does not apply to other websites that are accessible through this Site, including but not limited to any third-party websites that process payments on our behalf. Please be aware that third-party websites that process payments for Carly for President and websites for our advertisers, sponsors, affiliated entities and other third parties that are accessible through this Site may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such sites and will not be responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit. 

By submitting your email address to our campaign on our Site, you agree to receive emails from our campaign; you may unsubscribe at any time. Should you wish to opt-out of receiving emails from Carly for President, an unsubscribe link is included in every e-mail. If the link is not working properly, or if you wish to communicate your desire to opt-out, please reply to the email with "Unsubscribe" in the subject line.

Our site contains links to other websites and servers. The campaign does not bear responsibility for content on linked websites. Accordingly, you also agree that Carly for President will not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any such content, services on or through any such site or resource or goods. Carly for President provides links to original articles written and maintained by third parties. These links are provided as a convenience and do not imply a claim of ownership of that content.

We are committed to protecting the security of any personal information you provide to us. We maintain commercially reasonable safeguards to maintain the security and privacy of personal information that you provide to us. After you have submitted your information online to us, we recommend that you end your browser session before leaving your computer. In spite of these protections, we cannot guarantee the security of any data submitted over the Internet. After your information reaches us, however, it is stored on servers (or in the case of information received from you in person, in writing or over the phone, in physical storage areas) protected by procedures and technology designed to block reasonably foreseeable intrusions by unauthorized third parties. 

Your browser and other mechanisms may permit you to send do-not-track signals or other similar signals to express your preferences regarding online tracking. To the extent you employ such browser do-not-track signals or other similar mechanisms, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor such requests received by us to the extent we have the capacity and resources to identify and process your request. Due to the potential for rapid and diverse developments of technology in this area, we cannot guarantee that we can process every type of request that exists or may be developed in the future. As noted above, third parties, such as our advertising partners, may collect data that relates to you. We cannot control third parties' responses to do-not-track signals or other such mechanisms. Third parties' use of data relating to you and responsiveness to do-not-track signals is governed by their respective privacy policies. 

If you are a California resident, you have the right to request information from us regarding the manner in which we share certain categories of personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, in addition to the rights set forth above. Under California law, you have the right to send us a request at the designated address listed below to receive the following information:

1\. The categories of information we disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year;

2\. the names and addresses of the third parties that received the information; and

3\. if the nature of the third party's business cannot be determined from their name, examples of the products or services marketed.

This information may be provided in a standardized format that is not specific to you. The designated email address for these is cpp@carlyforpresident.com.

If you are accessing the Site from outside of the United States, you consent to the transfer of your information to the United States, and the processing, use, and sharing of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Regardless of where your information is collected or transferred, the information will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

While we do not intend to make changes to this privacy policy, we reserve the right to do so. If any changes to this privacy policy are made, the date that the revised or updated policy is posted to our site will appear at the bottom of the page.

If you have questions about these policies, please contact us by mail: Carly for President, PO BOX 7808, Merrifield, VA 22116-7809

Updated May 1, 2015.

**Contact Info**  
Carly for President  
PO BOX 7808  
Merrifield, VA 22116-7809
